OK so what is a compromise.
好的，所以什么是妥协。
Well you may already know but basically a compromise is when two people who disagree about something
好吧，您可能已经知道，但基本上妥协是两个人对某事意见不一
find a space in the middle where one side gives up something and the other side gives up something so
在中间找到一个空间，一边放弃一些东西，另一边放弃一些东西，所以
that they can agree so that they can come to some sort of agreement.
他们可以同意，以便他们可以达成某种协议。
So the parent who wants their son to study a lot after school is over here the parent who wants their
所以希望他们的儿子放学后学习很多的父母在这里
son to have a lot of free time after school is over here.
儿子放学后有很多空闲时间都在这里。
Well they need to meet in the middle.
好吧，他们需要在中间见面。
It's not going to be only this or only this.
不会只有这个或只有这个。
They need to find somewhere in the middle in this spectrum where they agree so that they can actually
他们需要在这个范围的中间找到他们同意的地方，这样他们才能真正
get somewhere.
到某个地方。
Right.
正确的。
So they have to find common ground.
所以他们必须找到共同点。
This space in the middle between the two extremes of the spectrum.
这个空间位于光谱的两个极端之间。
This is the spectrum.
这是光谱。
This area is common ground.
这个领域是共同点。
Maybe if our son takes four classes a week for extra classes a week then you'll still have time to hang
也许如果我们的儿子每周上四节课，每周加班，那么你还有时间挂
out with friends.
和朋友出去。
OK I could agree to three or four classes a week as long as he can do things he enjoys more creative
好的，我可以同意每周上三到四节课，只要他能做他喜欢做的更有创意的事情
things three times a week.
每周三件事。
Yes OK.
好的。
That sounds fair.
这听起来很公平。
So they're in here.
所以他们在这里。
Not on the extremes.
不走极端。
They have found common ground.
他们找到了共同点。
They've met in the middle.
他们在中间见过面。
They have.
他们有。
And this can be a noun or a verb.
这可以是名词或动词。
It can be a noun or a verb.
它可以是名词或动词。
They have made they have made a compromise.
他们已经做出了妥协。
They have they have compromised and that's a verb they have made a compromise.
他们已经妥协了，这是他们已经妥协的动词。
They have compromised.
他们妥协了。
OK so that's the meaning of compromise.
好的，这就是妥协的意思。
Now we can look at a couple of expressions when we're ready to compromise.
现在，当我们准备妥协时，我们可以看看几个表达式。
OK.
好的。
So let's look at a few of those.
那么让我们来看看其中的几个。
Now let's take that situation with the two parents who want to compromise.
现在让我们以这两个想要妥协的父母为例。
They have two different views on an issue and they want to compromise.
他们对一个问题有两种不同的看法，他们想妥协。
Well one parent might say I'll tell you what I'll tell you what.
那么一位家长可能会说我会告诉你我会告诉你什么。
So this is a way to suggest the compromise.
所以这是一种建议妥协的方式。
The thing that you're willing to give up.
你愿意放弃的东西。
Tell you what if he can take three classes a week and also play with his friends a few times a week
告诉你如果他可以每周上三节课，并且每周和他的朋友一起玩几次怎么办
then I think we have a deal.
那么我认为我们达成了协议。
I think we can agree.
我想我们可以同意。
Let's talk about a seller for example a seller wants to sell something a buyer wants to buy something.
让我们谈谈卖方，例如卖方想卖东西，买方想买东西。
Seller is giving a very high price.
卖家给出了非常高的价格。
Buyer doesn't want to pay a high price.
买家不想付出高昂的代价。
They want to pay a low price obviously.
他们显然想付出低价。
OK.
好的。
So they are at opposite ends of the spectrum.
因此，它们处于光谱的两端。
But the person in the shop who wants to buy something has made it very clear they don't want to pay
但是店里想买东西的人已经明确表示他们不想付钱
the full price.
全价。
They think it's too high.
他们认为这太高了。
The seller is ready to compromise to give up a little bit.
卖家准备妥协放弃一点。
So the seller might say Well I'll tell you what.
所以卖家可能会说好吧，我会告诉你什么。
Instead of 400 How about 350 we use How about as a way to recommend the new price.
我们使用 How about 作为推荐新价格的一种方式，而不是 400 How about 350。
It's very common.
这很常见。
And we'll look at another situation in a moment.
我们稍后再看另一种情况。
How about this.
这个怎么样。
How about this three hundred fifty and I'll give you a free.
这个三百五十怎么样，我给你一个免费的。
Whatever and something.
随便什么的。
How about this is to recommend it to suggest the new thing.
怎么样是推荐它来推荐新事物。
The compromise would you be willing to consider three hundred three hundred.
妥协你愿意考虑三百红三百。
That's my final offer although that wouldn't really be a compromise if you added that.
这是我的最终报价，尽管如果您添加它，那并不是真正的妥协。
But sometimes people say that final offer in a negotiation when you're bargaining with the seller.
但有时人们在与卖家讨价还价时会在谈判中说最终报价。
Bargaining with the seller would you be willing to consider this if you want to get somebody to do something
与卖家讨价还价，如果您想让某人做某事，您是否愿意考虑这一点
you can recommend it in this way.
你可以通过这种方式推荐它。
Would you be willing to consider helping me move my sofa tomorrow.
你愿意考虑明天帮我搬沙发吗？
Would you be willing to consider that.
你愿意考虑一下吗。
It's very very polite very gentle.
非常非常有礼貌非常温柔。
OK.
好的。
Could you meet me in the middle on this.
你能在这中间见我吗？
Now this one may not be used so much when it comes to price in a shop.
现在，在商店的价格方面，这个可能不会被太多使用。
Media could you could say could you meet me in the middle on this.
媒体你能说你能不能在这中间见我。
I think 300 is fair.
我认为300是公平的。
350 is still too high.
350还是太高了。
Could you meet me in the middle on this please.
你能在这中间见我吗？
All right.
好的。
All right I guess so.
好吧，我想是的。
You've got a deal.
你有一个交易。
OK.
好的。
Maybe maybe but I think this one is probably more common for situations more like the husband and the
也许也许，但我认为这可能更常见于更像丈夫和丈夫的情况
wife who disagree about their child.
对孩子意见不一的妻子。
Listen I just don't want him to be in class all day including after school.
听着，我只是不想让他整天上课，包括放学后。
I think it's reasonable that he should have some free time.
我认为他应该有一些空闲时间是合理的。
Could you meet me in the middle on this.
你能在这中间见我吗？
Let's find some common ground.
让我们找到一些共同点。
OK.
好的。
Now a couple more expressions we can use when we're in this sort of bargaining negotiation type situation
现在，当我们处于这种讨价还价谈判类型的情况时，我们可以使用更多的表达方式
negotiating by the way is what we're doing.
顺便说一句，我们正在做的就是谈判。
We are negotiating.
我们正在谈判。
If it's money that we're dealing with then we're bargaining we're bargaining when we're talking about
如果我们处理的是金钱，那么我们就是在讨价还价
money especially in a shop sometimes haggling but usually bargaining.
钱，尤其是在商店里有时讨价还价，但通常讨价还价。
I think what I'm asking is reasonable.
我认为我的要求是合理的。
Now this is just a comment.
现在这只是一个评论。
This is just a thing to say to sort of support the number you gave.
这只是为了支持您提供的数字而说的。
So four classes a week.
所以每周上四节课。
I think what I'm asking is is reasonable don't you.
我认为我的要求是合理的，不是吗。
Then the other side has to say something.
然后对方不得不说些什么。
Yes or no.
是还是不是。
Probably.
大概。
OK.
好的。
I'm not saying we have to do it my way or only my way but I think for example if one parent wants the
我并不是说我们必须按照我的方式或只能按照我的方式去做，但我认为，例如，如果一位家长想要
boy to take two classes every day after school.
男孩每天放学后要上两节课。
That would be my way.
那将是我的方式。
That's my way My way is what I want what I think is right.
这就是我的方式 我的方式就是我想要的，我认为是正确的。
In fact we have an interesting expression.
事实上，我们有一个有趣的表达方式。
My way or the highway my way or the highway it's my way or the highway.
我的方式或高速公路 我的方式或高速公路 这是我的方式或高速公路。
That means if you don't agree with what I think is right with what I want to do leave get on the highway
这意味着，如果你不同意我认为正确的做法和我想做的事，请上高速
go away.
离开。
It's like that.
就像那样。
It's my way or the highway.
这是我的方式或高速公路。
So when you're compromising you can't say that can't say my way or the highway.
所以当你妥协时，你不能说那不能说我的方式或高速公路。
If you want to compromise so I'm not saying we have to do it my way or I'm not saying we have to do
如果你想妥协，所以我不是说我们必须按照我的方式去做，或者我不是说我们必须这样做
it only my way means I'm willing to be flexible here.
只有我的方式意味着我愿意在这里灵活。
But I think it is important that he take some classes.
但我认为他参加一些课程很重要。
It's very important that he takes some classes so that he can stay ahead and compete with the other
他参加一些课程非常重要，这样他才能保持领先并与其他人竞争
students.
学生。
So this one is really good for negotiating in situations.
所以这个非常适合在情况下进行谈判。
We are talking about actions what should be done not usually about price and when you're ready to compromise.
我们正在谈论通常不应该在价格以及您准备妥协时采取的行动。
You can use these phrases to kind of support your side and and sort of explain your side to show that
您可以使用这些短语来支持您的立场，并解释您的立场以表明这一点
what you're saying is reasonable it's reasonable very reasonable.
你什么'说的是合理的很合理很合理。